Anthony Marshall - Resume

Personal Details

Address : Point Chevalier, Auckland, NZ Nationality : New Zealand Email Address : anthonymarshall@qmail.com Phone : 027 658 4855

LinkedIn Profile: <u>linkedin.com/in/anthonymarshallnz</u>

Portfolio Site : anthonymarshall.io

About Me

I'm a software developer who has 16 years commercial experience building many successful web, desktop and server based applications for a wide variety of companies and industries, such as utilities, finance, marking/advertising, retail and real estate.

My key technical experiences revolve around (but not limited to) both back and front end web development using the Microsoft stack of technologies. i.e C#, Asp.net, Sql Server, Html, CSS, JS (React with Redux)

I'm an avid sports fan, with Tennis and running being a great passion. I currently play for the Point Chevalier interclub tennis team.

Software Technology Experience

	Years Experience								
Technology	< 1	1	2	3	4	5	6+		
C# .Net									
Java									
ASP.Net MVC / Web Forms							•		
Mobile web developer									
Sharepoint									
SQL Server									
SQL DTS, SSIS, SSRS									
Crystal Reports									
Web frontend (HTML\CSS\JS\SASS\Angular\React)							•		
React JS	•								
PHP									
MySQL									
Oracle 9i & 10g									
Postgres									
GIT									

Linux Administration				
Teamcity (Continuous Integration)	•			
Team Foundation Server (TFS)				
Technical Lead		•		
Agile development (with Jira)				

Other Skills

- Advocate for Software Development best practices. E.g SOLID, DDD, TDD
- Exceptional verbal and written communication skills.
- Excellent time management skills and practices.
- Extensive client liaison and user training experience.
- Ability to quickly learn and adapt new development technologies.
- Extensive experience managing and mentoring developers.
- Experience writing client facing technical documentation.
- Ability and experience in successfully architect simple technical solutions for complex problems.

Education

2000 – 2003 : Auckland University of Technology

Bachelor of Applied Science (Software Development pathway)

Work Experience

New Zealand Government

October 2017 - Present

L3 Software Developer

Working as a senior developer using a variety of front and backend technologies.

Please contact me for more details.

Datacom NZ (<u>datacom.co.nz</u>)

February 2017 – October 2017

Full Stack Developer

Worked primarily for Datacom's client Barfoot & Thompson.

Key achievement was being the lead developer on Barfoot's SalesKit project from conception to release. This is a highly interactive web application used by sales agents to create and design professionally printed promotional material and property listing documentation.

Built using React, Redux, .Net, Sql Server This product has proven to be highly successful to Barfoot & Thompson, and is actively used by the business today.

BBD Perfect Storm London (bbdperfectstorm.com) (formerly Suburb Design London wearesuburb.com)

September 2012 – January 2017

Technical Lead / Senior Developer

Dual role of Technical Lead and Senior Developer (40/60 time split). Key responsibilities were to develop front and back end web and desktop applications, manage the development team (4 devs plus freelancers), define development processes, write technical documentation and be the technical contact for clients.

Key clients that I have worked with in this role were Investec, BP, Cadburys, Samsung, Converse, Japanese Tobacco International, De Beers and Kinder.

Tech stack used in this role: C#, Asp.net, WPF, Sql Server, Episerver, PHP, Laravel, Magento, MySql, HTML/CSS/JS, SASS, Angular 1 & 2, Git, AWS, Jenkins

Candi London (candi.co.uk)

June 2012 - August 2012

Freelance Senior .Net Developer (contract)

Digital agency servicing Morrisons supermarket. My role here was to help build new modules for the Morrisons online shopping website (www.morrisons.co.uk) and add integration with SalesForce

Tech stack used in this role: C#, Asp.net, Sql Server, Episerver, HTML/CSS/JS, Teamcity

Suburb Design London (<u>wearesuburb.com</u>)

January 2012 – June 2012

Freelance Senior .Net Developer (contract)

Suburb are a digital agency based in London who specialise in interactive art direction and design, website design and development, and social media app development.

I am was working here as a contract developer and have been involved in a number of projects coding (front and back-end) highly interactive, advertising campaign based websites and Facebook applications.

The fast paced nature of projects and tight deadlines in digital agencies such as Suburb allowed me to demonstrate that I was capable of producing quality code in a timely fashion to meet project demands.

Tech stack used in this role: C#, Asp.net, Sql Server, HTML/CSS/JS, LESS, SVN

AIMIA (<u>aimia.com</u>)

June 2007 – October 2011

(formerly Carlson Marketing Ltd)

Senior Analyst Programmer

AIMIA (formerly Carlson Marketing Ltd) is a world leading provider of customer and business loyalty programmes for many high profile multi-national companies, such as Vodafone, Westpac Bank and Pfizer. In this role I successfully developed a number of high-traffic, 100,000+ user, web based systems.

Systems that I have worked on include:

- <u>www.hotpoints.co.nz</u> Westpac bank's customer loyalty points redemption site
- www.truerewards.co.nz ASB bank's customer loyalty points redemption site

Tech stack used in this role : ASP.Net, C#, SQL Server, SQL DTS and SSIS, Crystal, Kentico CMS

Key Responsibilities:

Application development of high traffic, front-end and back-end transactional systems

- Database design and development
- B2B EDI design, development and implementation
- Technical documentation
- Implementation of multi-lingual systems
- Training and support for junior developers
- Liaising with external clients and in-house account managers
- Migration of legacy systems into modern development platforms (e.g Fox Pro -> .Net)

Kinetiq Ltd (www.kinetiq.com)

January 2005 - June 2007

Analyst Programmer

Kinetiq Ltd is an industry-leading provider of web and desktop based data management solutions for the international energy market. In this role I was the technical lead in a large project building a web based process management solution. I also help manage and develop a number of our other major software products.

Tech stack used in this role: ASP.Net, C#.Net, SQL Server and Oracle 10g

Edis International Ltd

May 2004 - December 2004

Software Developer

In this position I was hired as a software developer to work on developing B2B EDI message translation applications that work closely with various ERP systems. Messaging standards that I have become familiar with in this role were XML, ANSI x12 and EDIFACT. I was also responsible for other tasks within the organisation such as the development of EdisInternational.com website and software product testing.

Key technologies used in this position: VB6, VB.Net, ASP, Pervasive and SOL Server.

Blueday Ltd

May 2003 - May 2004

Software Developer

This was my first full-time position as an IT professional. I specialised in web development for small to medium sized businesses. This role involved a number of responsibilities relating to the development of successful IT solutions.

Tech stack used in this role: Classic ASP, ASP.net and SQL Server.

Online Talent Agency

August 2002 - July 2003

Student software developer

In the final year research and development project for my degree, I was involved the development of a web-based system, which enabled my client (Background Talent. Talent agency that specialises in managing extras, actors and production crews for TV and Film) to perform key business processes through a highly functional web application. This system has proved to be highly successful in providing significant growth in business for my client. Software products developed in this project is still being used today.

Key technologies used in this position: PHP, MySQL and Apache.

References

Available on request